We're going to talk about first order logic,
我们将要讨论一阶逻辑
and its relation to the other logics we've seen so
及其与我们学习过的
far, namely propositional logic and probability theory.
命题逻辑和概率论的关系
And we're going to talk about them in terms of what they say about the world,
我们将要根据他们表现世界的内容进行探讨
which we called the ontological commitment of these logics and
即这些逻辑的本体化承诺和
what types of beliefs agents can have using these logics,
使用这些逻辑主体需要具备哪种类型的可信度
which we call the epistemological commitments.
即所谓的认识论承诺
So in first order logic, we have relations about things in the world,
那么在一阶逻辑中 我们包括世界上事件之间
objects, and functions on those objects.
对象之间和这些对象的函数之间的联系
And what we can believe about those relations is that they're true,
并且我们认为这些关系为真
or false, or unknown.
假或未知
So this is an extension of propositional logic in which all we have
所以这是对命题逻辑的延伸
was facts about the world and we could believe that those facts were true,
命题逻辑中 我们了解到世界的事实 然后认定这些事实为真
or false, or unknown.
假或未知
Now, in probability theory, we have the same types of facts
现在在概率论中 我们拥有与命题逻辑 符号或变量
as in propositional logic, the symbols, or variables, but
相同类型的事实 但是
the beliefs could be a real number in the range zero to one.
可信度可以是 0 到 1 之间的实数
So logics vary both in what you can say about the world and
所以根据对世界描述的内容
what you can believe about what's been said about the world.
和我们如何认识描述的内容 逻辑各不相同
Another way to look at representation is to break the world up
我们要看的另一个表示法是将世界
into representations that are atomic, meaning that a representation
拆分成原子表现法 即表现状态
of the state is just an individual state when no piece is inside of it.
只是对个体状态的表现 内部不包含其他内容
And that's what we used for search and problem solving.
这就是我们用于检索和解决问题的方法
We had a state like state A and
我们这里有个状态 状态 A
then we transition to another state like state B, and
然后转化成另一个状态 状态 B
all we can say about those states was, are they identical to each other or not?
我们可以说这些状态中 它们是否完全一致？
And maybe, is one of them a goal state or not?
或者其中一个是目标状态吗？
But there wasn't any internal structure to those states.
不过这些状态中没有内部结构
Now in propositional logic as well as in probability theory,
在命题逻辑和概率论中
we break up the world into a set of facts that are true or false.
我们把世界拆分成一系列真或假的事实
So we call this a factored representation, that is representation
我们称之为因素化表示
that an individual state of the world is factored into several variables,
即世界的个体状态通过不同因素成为一些变量
the B and E and A and M and J, for example.
例如 B E A M 和 J
And those could be Boolean variables or,
这些在一些表示类型中可以是布尔变量
in some types of representations, not in propositional logic.
但在命题逻辑中不是布尔变量
They can be other types of variables besides Boolean.
除了布尔变量 它们还可以是其他类型的变量
Then the third type,
然后是第三类
the most complex type of representation we call structured.
最复杂的表示法类型 称为结构化表示法
And then the structured representation,
在结构化表示法中
an individual state is not just a set of values for variables,
个体状态并不只是变量的一些值
but it can include relationships between objects, a branching structure, and
还包括对象 分支结构和复杂表示法之间的关系
complex representations and relations between one object and another.
以及一个对象与另一个对象的关系
And that's what we see in traditional programming languages.
这就是我们在传统编程语言中看到的内容
It's what we see in database.
这是我们在数据库中看到的内容
They're called structured databases.
它们称为结构化数据库
And we have structured query languages over those databases.
我们在这些数据库中构建查询语言
And that's a most powerful representation.
这是非常强大的表示法
And that's what we get in first order logic.
这是我们在一阶逻辑中学习的内容